Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The Zabi family seeks to impose dictatorship
over all of humanity...
...ruling from the Principality of Zeon...
...a gigantic space city-state
floating beyond the moon.
Sovereign Degwin Zabi ceded his power
to his eldest son, Gihren Zabi...
...and war broke out.
Faced with the superior preparation
of the Zeon forces...
...the Earth Federation Forces
were helpless.
Avoiding Zeon's attacks and
escaping from Side 7...
...the White Base, piloted by
its youthful crew, returned to Earth.
After bringing down Garma Zabi,
the youngest member of the Zabi family...
...it is currently crossing the Pacific Ocean.
The Threat of Zeon
I will be returning to Zeon for a while
within two months or so.
But Father...
...before I return, I promise you
a military triumph.
I don't want our people
to laugh at me because...
...I earned my promotion by being your son.
Well then, I look forward
to seeing you soon.
Are you still here?
I do understand how you feel. However...
...given your position as Sovereign...
...I beg you to carry out your duties.
I know that.
Zabi! Zabi...!
Zabi! Zabi!
Zabi! Zabi! Zabi!
What's this "interesting" thing you found?
Sir! We've caught a warship that's not
on our identification charts.
Hm. Show me.
We believe it may be that Trojan Horse.
Could this be a chance
to avenge Lord Garma?
Don't be so hasty, Hamon.
Their position is quite a distance
from our base.
We need to factor in our cruising range.
The Zanzibar can certainly make it, but...
...the rest of our force is only made up of
atmospheric entry capsules.
Yes, that's right.
Then, are you going to simply let them go?
My mission is to avenge Garma's death.
I'm not going to ignore
direct orders from Admiral Dozle.
But we're in the middle of atmospheric
entry. Please don't take unnecessary risks.
But don't you hate the kind of man
who would let someone pass by...
...without lifting a finger to stop them?
Amuro, I'm coming in.
Repairs again?
Yeah.
Amuro, feeling down. Amuro.
Think so?
What is that?
The Gundam's spare computer.
Amuro, eat before it gets cold.
All right.
Amuro, brainwave levels low.
Levels...
I'm fine, Haro.
Haro, don't disturb him. Come with me.
See you later. I'll come pick up your tray.
I'd better eat.
The main engine's third nozzle
has 2% less thrust than displayed.
How much is that, in concrete terms?
About 40 tons.
Why did we leave it until it got this bad?!
We haven't had time
for proper maintenance, and...
This isn't a playground! Get out of here!
Mr. Bright!
We're not playing!
We're... not playing...!
Check the third nozzle.
I'm taking a break, Mirai.
A-All right.
I'm sorry. Please continue cleaning.
We're counting on you.
Go ahead.
What is it?
Nothing.
I know what you want to say.
I'm sure you do.
You have to be the responsible one.
After all, everyone relies on you.
I have a hard time believing that.
What is it?
It's Zeon. It looks like
an atmospheric entry capsule...
...but it seems too big for that.
I'll be right there.
What has been done about Char?
He probably went back home.
Right, Dozle?
Is that so.
Yes, my lady. Right away.
Block number 6 is hit!
Can't we shake them off?
Impossible!
They're using speed from the entry,
and our engines are...
Let's head into those clouds, starboard side.
We'll be going into a thunder storm.
Are you sure...?
Yes. The beam cannon's power
will be halved, but...
We have no choice.
Roger, sir.
Wh-What was that?!
Maybe it's a new Zeon weapon!
Don't worry. No matter what new weapon
attacks, the Gundam will protect us.
Lieutenant!
The Federation's got a new weapon!
Don't panic!
This is what's known on Earth as lightning.
Darling...
I've seen this before, on Earth.
It's all right, Hamon.
Although it does look frightening
up close like this.
Yes. But now that we know
this is what they call lightning...
let us continue pursuing the Trojan Horse.
Port-side main engine losing power!
That earlier hit is affecting it!
Not good... especially at a time like this.
How's the E.C.M?
It's transmitting at maximum output.
Mirai. We're going to have to land
somewhere and wait this out.
Right now, we're just
wasting Minovsky particles.
Can you do it?
I'll try.
Forward infrared observation monitor open.
Begin laser sensor terrain scan!
There!
Confirm direction and approach angle!
Can you do it, Mirai?
Y-Yes.
The White Base is at zero speed.
All right. Well done, Mirai.
Gundam! Guncannon! Guntank!
Prepare for sortie! Open anti-aircraft fire!
Amuro!
I didn't want to believe it, but are you still...?
Hey! Amuro!
Amuro! Amuro!
Get it together! We have a sortie!
Mr. Ryu...
Zoning out in your room
won't do any good!
Mr. Ryu...
Come on! Get up! Up!
I understand. You don't have to hit me.
The Trojan Horse has completely vanished.
They've slipped out of the laser search net.
They can't have escaped from this storm.
Keep searching for as long as
we can stay in the air.
Yes sir!
Releasing 180 degree infrared camera.
No response on sonar sensor.
There are a lot of islands in this area.
Yes, sir.
How inconvenient.
If we could use the radar,
we'd find them right away.
Please don't. I can do it myself.
You're sure?
Yes.
I'm not sure he's up to it.
This helmet feels strange.
It's suffocating me.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Just keep going past us...
There's no mistake?
Yes. The magnetic response is too strong.
Send out an FW flare.
Lieutenant Ramba Ral,
we've just sighted a flare.
To the rear, at 7 o'clock.
You're sure it's not lightning?
Yes, sir!
All right! Hard turn!
Enemy approaching!
Open main cannons!
Gundam, Guncannon! Prepare for launch!
Fire even if you can't see anything!
Launch missiles, too!
So, that's the famous Trojan Horse.
Get all the data you can.
Fire!
Rather than watching you sit around
like a commander...
...I much prefer seeing you like this,
going into battle.
I feel the same way.
I think this suits me better.
See you. Don't let the soldiers interfere.
All right.
Acous! Cozun! Are you ready?
Yes, Lieutenant!
Preparation status OK!
Acous, Cozun, this is our first time
fighting on Earth.
Even if the enemy mobile suit appears...
...don't pursue it too far.
Roger!
Hamon, I'm off!
I wish you victory.
Don't fret, Hamon.
I'm terribly sorry...
...but we cannot remain airborne
at this place any longer.
Thank you for your assistance.
Go ahead to base. We'll follow soon.
Roger. We wish you success.
What does this mean, Bright?
The Komusais are leaving.
Probably low on fuel.
We have a better chance at winning now.
Gundam, Guncannon,
why aren't you launching?
The Zakus are on the ground!
Well, to tell the truth,
Amuro's got that rookie syndrome!
What?!
Make Amuro sortie as well!
It's the only thing that will stop the Zakus.
Sink or swim, huh?
Amuro! We have a sortie!
Amuro! Let's go! We're launching!
Amuro! We're about to launch! Okay?!
Amuro, do you read?
The catapult connection is complete.
You are launching.
Huh? Oh, yeah, Ms. Sayla.
I can't hear you!
It's okay. I'm launching, right?
Never mind, Sayla!
Just launch the Gundam!
Roger!
Pull it together, Amuro!
What was that?!
Is that a Zaku? No, it can't be...!
Z-Zaku...
No... It's a new mobile suit!
A new Zeon mobile suit?!
Ryu! Kai! Give Amuro some backup!
White Base turrets, give him fire cover!
All right! Here I go!
Stop all fire!
Damn!
Acous! Throw the cracker!
What's that?
Why you...!
Well, this is something.
But can it withstand the heat rod?
Impressive!
That mobile suit's pilot is pretty good.
I'm surprised he wasn't blown apart
by his own bazooka.
Lieutenant Ral, on your right!
What?!
There's another one coming out.
That thing's a mobile suit too?!
Hurry up, Hayato!
Give him covering fire!
I'm worried about Amuro.
Acous, Cozun, you handle
the two mobile suits in back.
I'll go after the white one.
I'll get you! I'll finish you!
I don't care if you're a new mobile suit!
Amuro! Don't get too close to him!
His weapon...!
Not bad!
This is no Zaku, boy! No Zaku!
This one's different!
It's got more armor and power than a Zaku.
Get up, Amuro!
Acous, Cozun, retreat!
We're heading back!
Roger, sir!
They're on board! Engage lock, quickly!
Message to the bridge.
Prepare the blinding flood lights.
We're leaving the battlefield.
Wha...! What's that?!
They ran away...
Or rather, they spared us.
We have lost a hero!
But does this mean our defeat?!
No! It is a new beginning!
Zeon's national strength is less than
1/30th that of the Earth Federation.
In spite of that, how is it that
we've been able to fight for so long?
My people!
It is because the Principality of Zeon's
aims in this war are just!
Zeon is broadcasting this live
all over the world, just to annoy us.
You should watch too, Amuro.
Yes, sir.
It has been over fifty years
since a handful of elites...
...took control of the Earth Federation,
which had extended its reach into space.
We, who live in space,
asked for our freedom!
Remember how many times the Federation
trampled us underfoot!
The Principality of Zeon is fighting
for the freedom of all of humanity...
...and God will not turn his back on us!
My younger brother...
...the Garma Zabi
that you all loved is dead!
Why?!
Because he was a spoiled kid.
The fighting has died down somewhat.
Perhaps many of you see this war
as someone else's problem!
Bartender!
But that is a mistake! The Federation...
That one's on me. If you don't mind?
...has polluted the Earth out of greed...
You're with the Royal Guard.
Can you tell?
It's the smell. You're one of Kycilia's.
We must expose the foolishness...
...of the Earth Federation elites...
You're as good as they say, Lt. Commander.
Garma died in order to wake you
out of your wishful thinking.
This is only the beginning of our war.
Amuro, are you all right?
We are building up our military.
Sorry to worry you. I'm all right.
The Earth Federation will do the same.
Do your best.
Thanks.
Many of your fathers and brothers...
...died due to the Federation's
ill-judged resistance!
We must never forget
this anger and sorrow!
Garma has shown us this
through his own death!
By focusing our collective anger
right at this moment...
...and bringing it down upon the Federation,
we will finally grasp true victory!
Victory is the greatest tribute
that we can pay to those who have fallen!
Rise, my people!
Take your sorrow and turn it into anger!
Zeon thirsts for your strength!
Sieg Zeon!
Sieg Zeon!!
This is our enemy?!
What a bunch of nonsense!
This from a man who's seeking
a Zabi family dictatorship!
Sieg Zeon!!
Dictatorship...
Amuro's childhood home is a place
where ally and enemy tangle...
...and people live with despairing hearts.
As the son encounters his mother...
...misfortune threatens them both.
Seeing his mother again...
...does not bring Amuro peace of mind.
Next episode, on Mobile Suit Gundam...
Coming Home.
Next Time
Coming Home
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...